Hari Sharma fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Research files, 1976 - 2009; F-251-4; 1.25 m of textual records
  - Conference and seminar notes, lectures, and proceedings, 1979 - 2006; F-251-4-3; 26 cm of textual records
    - Kampuchea: Support Committee publications, 1979 - 1990; F-251-4-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Kampuchea Tokyo Conference (June 1981), F-251-4-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Italian-Kampuchean Association notes (June 1, 1981), F-251-4-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - The Failure of the Cultural Revolution and Deng Xiaoping's Revisionism, Tomas Brunila, 1983; F-251-4-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Three Essays on the Crisis of Marxism-Leninism-Maoism, By Revolutionary Alternative Movement ITU, Finland, 1984; F-251-4-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Kampuchea Bangkok Conference (July 1987), F-251-4-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Lecture notes on communalism/class/ethnicity/nation, 1988 - 1994; F-251-4-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - URPE summer conference, Aug. 27-30, 1992, F-251-4-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Association for Asian Studies Conference, Los Angeles (March 1993), F-251-4-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Perspectives of the International Revolution, Speeches by Jose Maria Sison and Stefan Engel at the Sixth Youth Festival of MLPD and REBELL in Essen, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Seize the Day, Seize the Hour Commemorating Mao Zedong,By Pal Steigan, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - On the Theory of Continuation of Revolution under the Dictatorship of Proletariat, By Carlos Echague, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Tribute to the Great Communist Mao Zedong, By Amado Guerrero, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Mao: A Great Leader of the International Proletariat and of Oppressed Nations and Peoples, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Matti Puolakka thought: The Revolutionary Ideology of 21st Century?, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Mao Tsetung Thought and the Doctrine of the Mode of Thinking, By Stefan Engel, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 251-55)
    - Materials from the International Seminar on Mao Zedong 100th Birth Anniversary Celebration in Gelsenkirchen, Germany, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Jose Maria Sison at the International Seminar on Mao Zedong Thought - 1993 Nov. 6, F-251-4-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - A Contribution to the Discussion on Mao Tse Toung, By A/Synechia, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-19 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Theory and Strategic Line of People's War, By Karrim Essack, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-20 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Can Dragons Swap Pearls with the Dragon God of the Sea, By William Hinton, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-21 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Mao Socialist Line in Chinese Agriculture, By William Hinton, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-22 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Mao Zedong and Social Imperialism, By Carlos Echague, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-23 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Reflections on a Conversation with Comrade Mao Zedong, By Otto Vargas, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-24 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Mao: Great Leader of the International Proletariat and Oppressed Nations and Peoples, By Giovanni Scuderi, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-25 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - The 100th Birth Anniversary of Mao Zedong Marks the Triumph of His Ideas over Modern Revisionism, By Dieter Klauth and Klaus Arnecke, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-26 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Revolution in Imperialist Countries Requires Marxism-Leninism-Maoism, By Lenny Wolff, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-27 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Maoism and the (Mis)application of the Chinese Revolutionary Model in the Postwar Japan Communist Movement, By Gary P. Leupp, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-28 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Mao Tsetung's Last Great Battle, 1973-76: The High Road of Revolution, By Raymond Lotta, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-29 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Women in 20th Century China - The Maoist Legacy, By Carol Andreas, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-30 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - The Literary Legacy of Chairman Mao in the Philippines, By E.A. Ordonez, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-31 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Mao Zedong's Revolutionary Aesthetics and Its Influence on the Philippine Struggle, By Alice G. Guillermo, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-32 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Lasting Significance of the Mao-Model for Third World Countries, By Wim F. Wertheim, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-33 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Mass Movement -- Mao's Socialist Strategy for Change, By D.Y. Hsu and P.Y. Ching, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-34 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Labor Reform -- Mao Vs. Liu-Deng, By D.Y. Hsu and P.Y. Ching, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-35 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - 100 Years Mao Tsetung - Rebellion is justified!, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-36 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Maozedong on Art and Culture, By Alice G. Guillermo, 1993; F-251-4-3-0-37 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Punjab Conference, UK (June 1994), F-251-4-3-0-38 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - JNU/Social Conference, Dec. 1994, F-251-4-3-0-39 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Academic, 1994 - 1997; F-251-4-3-0-40 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Beyond Economic Growth: Options for China's Development, Dr. Paul Lin, 1995; F-251-4-3-0-41 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - No to APEC (November 1997, Vancouver), F-251-4-3-0-42 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - North American Conference: Peace & Human Rights in India and Pakistan, 1999; F-251-4-3-0-43 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - The Korea International War Crimes Tribunal, 2001; F-251-4-3-0-44 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Korea trip, June 2003, F-251-4-3-0-45 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Korea World Peace Conference, Seoul - June 2003, F-251-4-3-0-46 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - Sison: Laws, Labels, Liberation (Montreal), 2004; F-251-4-3-0-47 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
    - International Dalit Conference, 2003; F-251-4-3-0-48
    - Bangla leaflet translation and invitation to conference at Calcutta University, 2006; F-251-4-3-0-49 (Archival box - standard 251-56)
  - South Asia research files, 1980 - 2008; F-251-4-4; 37 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records arising from Hari Sharma's research activity on the politics of India and other nations in South Asia. Includes newspaper clippings, articles, correspondence, notes, book lists, and other materials.
    - Mitali, [ca 1980] - [ca 1990]; F-251-4-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - unidentified documents in Hindi?, [ca 1980] - [ca 1990]; F-251-4-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - unidentified documents in Hindi?, [ca 1980] - [ca 1990]; F-251-4-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Final Solutions By Mahesh Daltari, [ca 1980] - [ca 1990]; F-251-4-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Bihar data (Shalendra), [ca 1980]; F-251-4-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Nepal, 1986 - 1989; F-251-4-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Notes on India Waits - J. Myrdal, 1987 - 1992; F-251-4-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Aparna Sindhoor, 1990; F-251-4-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Communist Party of India (Marxist-Leninist), [ca 1991]; F-251-4-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Court papers re. Sardar Sarovar and background information, 1993 - 1995; F-251-4-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 251-57)
    - Correspondence re. Manibeli Declaration, 1994; F-251-4-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Correspondence from independent film makers re. Narmada Valley, 1994; F-251-4-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - HANS (Hindi monthly of creative writing), [ca 1994]; F-251-4-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Ambedkar/caste, etc., 1994 - 1996; F-251-4-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - India under "reforms", 1995 - 2004; F-251-4-4-0-15 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Meera's Films, etc., 1996 - 1998; F-251-4-4-0-16 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - India - Polity - BJP/Hindutava, Shivsena, 1996 - 2002; F-251-4-4-0-17 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Misc. Politics/India/Diaspora, [ca 1997] - [ca 2001]; F-251-4-4-0-18 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Writing project research, 1997 - 2007; F-251-4-4-0-19 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - BCAS (Bulletin of Atomic Scientists), 1998; F-251-4-4-0-20 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Nuclear Arms, 1998 - 1999; F-251-4-4-0-21 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - Notes relating to media coverage of India and politics, 1998 - 1999; F-251-4-4-0-22 (Archival box - standard 251-58)
    - The Bomb and India-Pakistan, 1998 - 1999; F-251-4-4-0-23 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Indian Elections, 1998 - 2000; F-251-4-4-0-24 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - On U.S. / India Nuke Deal, 1998 - 2008; F-251-4-4-0-25 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - India Travels - discussion notes, 1999 - 2000; F-251-4-4-0-26 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - The National Convention for Nuclear Disarmament and Peace (New Delhi), 2000; F-251-4-4-0-27 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Shastri, 2000 - 2002; F-251-4-4-0-28 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Gujarat Genocide (writiings), 2002; F-251-4-4-0-29 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - U.S. Nuclear Issues/Black Market, U.S. Military Doctrine (Pakistan) newspaper clipping, 2003 - 2007; F-251-4-4-0-30 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Bhopal Campaign, 2005 - 2007; F-251-4-4-0-31 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Nandigram, 2007; F-251-4-4-0-32 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - On Nandigram and SEZs, 2007; F-251-4-4-0-33 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - India: Politics/economics (book titles), [ca 2007]; F-251-4-4-0-34 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Burma: Crackdown, Oct. 2007 (newspaper clippings), 2007 - 2008; F-251-4-4-0-35 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - No One Is Illegal (NOII) / Laibar Singh, 2007 - 2008; F-251-4-4-0-36 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Pakistan, Emergency, Bhutto, 2007 - 2008; F-251-4-4-0-37 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Misc. (notes re. politics), [ca 2007] - [ca 2008]; F-251-4-4-0-38 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
    - Political prisoners, 2007 - 2008; F-251-4-4-0-39 (Archival box - standard 251-59)
- Publication and exhibition files, 1951 - 2006; F-251-5; 88 cm of textual records
  Series consists of the organizational records of Rainbow Publishers as well as literary works, photographic essays, and scholarly writing by Sharma that relates to sociology and political science. Includes correspondence and publicity materials associated with gallery exhibitions of his photographic essays.
  The arrangement was provided by the archivist and based on the type of records in the sub-series. Files are arranged chronologically.
  Textual records; Photographic materials; Graphic materials
  - Rainbow Publishers records, 1995 - 2002; F-251-5-1; 13 cm of textual records; Rainbow Publishers
    Rainbow Publishers Limited is a publishing house in India founded by a group of intellectuals, activists, and public figures that included Hari Sharma. The venture originated at the Convention Against Communalism and the Threat to Diversity held in Calcutta in 1986. The convention brought together like-minded individuals who were united in their thinking around social, cultural, and ecological justice in India. Their collaboration led to the founding of Rainbow Publishers. A main objective of Rainbow Publishers was to inexpensively make more available works on Marxism and socialism in South Asia. Today, Rainbow Publishers continues to publish and translate works of established and new writers in various languages.
    Sub-series consists of correspondence, announcements, notes, publicity, and financial information created, made, and/or received by Hari Sharma as one of the founders of Rainbow Publications. The publication house began as a venture initiated by Sharma, his friends, and comrades in India to inexpensively make available in India works on Marxism and socialism published in the English-speaking world.
    Rainbow Publishers; Textual records
    - Rainbow: Bettelheim, 1995 - 1996; F-251-5-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow: Paresh Chattopadhyay, 1995 - 1997; F-251-5-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow: Misc. correspondence, 1995 - 1997; F-251-5-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow: S. Amin, 1995 - 1997; F-251-5-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow: W. Hinton, 1995 - 1997; F-251-5-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow: Correspondence - India (Santoush/Dhruva, etc.), 1995 - 2001; F-251-5-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow Publishers: Announcements, etc., [ca 1998]; F-251-5-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow/Misc./Books/Accounts, 1998 - 2002; F-251-5-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
    - Rainbow: Chomsky, 2000; F-251-5-1-0-9 (Archival box - standard 251-60)
  - Poetry, prose, and photography, 1951 - 2006; F-251-5-2; 50 cm of textual records; Language: Includes poetry and stories translated into Punjabi and other languages.
    Sub-series consists of poetry, prose, and photography created by Hari Sharma. Includes correspondence, drawing books, sketches, lists of exhibits, translations, publications, essays, publicity, applications, photographic prints, reviews, and publications in which his works appeared.
    Textual records; Photographic materials
    - Correspondence: Writers, editors, etc., 1963 - 1998; F-251-5-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Rajendra Yadav and Manno Bhandan, 1970 - 1986; F-251-5-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Political, Academics / India, 1974 - 1986; F-251-5-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Gautum/Siddartha, 1976 - 1987; F-251-5-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Indian movies, etc., 1977; F-251-5-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Gursharan Singh/Amritsar, 1981 - 1987; F-251-5-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Navtej Bharati / Photo book, 1982 - 1987; F-251-5-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Stories / Photo book, 1982 - 1987; F-251-5-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Bengali book, 1982 - 1988; F-251-5-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Misc. Academics / India, 1984 - 1988; F-251-5-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Punjab University, 1985 - 1988; F-251-5-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Revolutionary Cultural Organization, 1985 - 1987; F-251-5-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Journals / Publishers / Books, 1998; F-251-5-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 251-61)
    - Writings, [ca 1951] - [ca 1957]; F-251-5-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - In Print: Stories, [ca 1952] - [ca 1954]; F-251-5-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Writings, [ca 1956] - [ca 1963]; F-251-5-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Drawings, 1958 - 1959; F-251-5-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Drawing Book, [ca 1960]; F-251-5-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Coming Back - by Hari Prakash Sharma, [ca 1960]; F-251-5-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Sketchbook, [ca 1960]; F-251-5-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Writing - research, notes, [ca 1962]; F-251-5-2-0-21 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - To revise/re-write (poems, photos), [ca 1969] - [ca 1973]; F-251-5-2-0-22 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Photos, no poems (copies), [ca 1970]; F-251-5-2-0-23 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Photos/poems (full sets), [ca 1978] - [ca 1980]; F-251-5-2-0-24 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Poems - Hindi translations, [ca 1978] - [ca 1980]; F-251-5-2-0-25 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Photos - working lists for shows, exhibits, [ca 1982] - [ca 1985]; F-251-5-2-0-26 (Archival box - standard 251-62)
    - Stories: unfinished, [ca 1970] - [ca 1989]; F-251-5-2-0-27 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Magazine/journal reproductions, 1975 - 1985; F-251-5-2-0-28 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Punjabi translations - photos/poems, 1982 - 1983; F-251-5-2-0-29 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Delhi Show Reviews, 1984 - 2000; F-251-5-2-0-30 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Poems - German translations, [199-] - [ca 2000]; F-251-5-2-0-31 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Photos - sales/collectors, etc., [199-] - [ca 2000]; F-251-5-2-0-32 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Photography and writing exhibits, 1998; F-251-5-2-0-33 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Nuclear Terror in the Economy of Scarcity Symposium - publicity poster and Surrey Art Gallery press release, 1998; F-251-5-2-0-34 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - 1998 Surrey show - people's comments, F-251-5-2-0-35 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Comments on Indian photo essay, 1998; F-251-5-2-0-36
    - Photo show (Millennium), 1998; F-251-5-2-0-37 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Surrey Art Gallery show opening (photos), 1998; F-251-5-2-0-38 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Photo Exhibition: 10-11/98 (Surrey): Working file, 1999; F-251-5-2-0-39 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Photos: Exhibition Notices, 1999; F-251-5-2-0-40 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Photo Show (India), 1999 - 2000; F-251-5-2-0-41 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Shastri Application, 1999 - 2000; F-251-5-2-0-42 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Lists for photo-poem sets, 2000; F-251-5-2-0-43 (Archival box - standard 251-63)
    - Burnaby - Gallery at Ceperley House, 2000; F-251-5-2-0-44 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Photos from Delhi exhibit opening, 2000; F-251-5-2-0-45 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Guest book with notes on photo exhibits, 2000; F-251-5-2-0-46 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Canada Council Grant Application (India show), 2000 - 2001; F-251-5-2-0-47 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Publications featuring visual and literary works of Hari Sharma, 1983 - 2001; F-251-5-2-0-48 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Sketches, 2000; F-251-5-2-0-49 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - The Dolls Speak - Francoise Bosteels (book), 2000; F-251-5-2-0-50 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Correspondence from British Columbia Arts Council, 2001; F-251-5-2-0-51 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Kamloops Art Gallery, 2001; F-251-5-2-0-52 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - Surrey Art Galery - Connections: 4 Artists' Projects, 2001; F-251-5-2-0-53 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
    - From "The Dolls Speak, 2002 - 2004; F-251-5-2-0-54 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
      - Dolls Speak, 2005; F-251-5-2-0-54-1 (Optical disc: cd-r OBJ-4044)
    - Through the Needle's Eye: Everyday Life of Everyday People - Francoise Bosteels (book), 2006; F-251-5-2-0-55 (Archival box - standard 251-64)
  - Socio-political writings, 1960 - 2006; F-251-5-3; 25 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of notes, interview transcripts, resources, and copies of publications written by Hari Sharma on politics in India, racism of Indo-Canadians in B.C., and other related subjects from critical, academic, and activist perspectives. Includes translated articles and works by other authors.
    - Hari Sharma interviewing Mr. Ranjit Hall in Ottawa, [196-?]; F-251-5-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Spanish publication that includes original poems by Sharma written in the 1960s, F-251-5-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Problems of Rural Change - includes paper by Hari Sharma: Land Reforms in a Village in the Union Territory of Delhi, 1963; F-251-5-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Photocopy of "Land Reforms in a Village in the Union Territory of Delhi", 1963; F-251-5-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Factional Politics in North Indian Village - Abstract, 1968; F-251-5-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Factional Politics in North Indian Village - original typed Doctoral thesis, Cornell University, 1968; F-251-5-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Factional Politics in North Indian Village - supporting documents, research, 1968; F-251-5-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Sociology of Revolution - speaking notes, 1968; F-251-5-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Social Sciences and Development, [ca 1969]; F-251-5-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Caste and Occupational Mobility in a Delhi Village, 1971; F-251-5-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - The Green Revolution in India: Prelude to a Red One?, 1973; F-251-5-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - From Factionalism to Class Polarisation: A Case Study in Changing Local-level Politics in India, 1974; F-251-5-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - "National Emergency" in India, 1975; F-251-5-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - On the Caste System Upside Down, 1975; F-251-5-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Publications in French, 1975; F-251-5-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 251-65)
    - Art and Revolutionary Praxis: A Further Comment on the Film "Aakrosh", 1981; F-251-5-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Institutional Racism and the Labour Market: The Case of British Columbia's Farmworkers, 1982; F-251-5-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Vancouver Sun: Cracks in the fortress, 1982; F-251-5-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Aakrosh: A Work of Art with Purpose, 1983; F-251-5-3-0-19 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - India 1984, 1985; F-251-5-3-0-20 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Political Development and Modernization, 1985; F-251-5-3-0-21 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Beyond Ethnicity and Class: Uniting People in the Fight Against Racism, A Study of a Social Movement in British Columbia, 1991; F-251-5-3-0-22 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - "Commentary", for CBC National Program (Radio), January 13, 1993, F-251-5-3-0-23 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - India and Concerned American Scholarship, 1993; F-251-5-3-0-24 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Using Contradictions to Make New Democratic Revolution, 1993; F-251-5-3-0-25 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Samir Amin: An Introduction, 1994; F-251-5-3-0-26 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - The Bretton Woods Institutions and Concerned Asian Scholarship, 1995; F-251-5-3-0-27 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - The Fiftieth Year: Looking Back, Looking Forward, 1997; F-251-5-3-0-28 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Oppose APEC! Oppose Imperialist Globalization! Build Anti-imperialist Movement, In Canada and Everywhere, 1997; F-251-5-3-0-29 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Vancouver Sun: Reflections on India's independence, 1997; F-251-5-3-0-30 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - The Quest for Nuclear-free World, 1998; F-251-5-3-0-31 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Vancouver Sun: India ended the nuclear balancing act by succumbing to arms race madness, 1998; F-251-5-3-0-32 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Nuclear Terror and Human Rights: India and Pakistan in focus, 1998; F-251-5-3-0-33 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Changing profile of Indo-Canadians in BC, Canada, 1999; F-251-5-3-0-34 (Archival box - standard 251-66)
    - Introduction featured in Bulletin of Concerned Asian Scholars, Vol. 31, No. 2, 1999; F-251-5-3-0-35 (Archival box - standard 251-66)